hi everybody welcome back to the channel
and today we are going to switch back to
this camera hi yes
the Fuji is back up and running and
today we're gonna look at
no sugar ice cream
keto friendly
so if you want to know how to enjoy the
best luxury ice cream possible without
any sugar in it stick around and we'll
talk about it
Rebel ice cream caught my eye online
it's a keto friendly ice cream available
in the US couldn't get it back in the UK
it's can't get it here but
but a lot of people have asked about
sugar-free options now
if you look at trying to break down some
of these sugar-free option recipes
excuse me when I continue drinking my
coffee
you're going to go down a rabbit hole
that it is borderline dangerous because
you can't actually figure out what
they've done
now I
spent a while trying to
figure out exactly how Rebel do their
ice cream specifically the coffee chip
flavor if you know me I like my coffee
and looking at my notes I'll put a an
image of these on the screen so you can
see I'm talking about
per tub
so
per pint I should say rather than per
tub they have this breakdown of
ingredients which is cream water
erythritol chicory root fiber which is
likely inulin
egg yolks coffee vegetable glycerin milk
protein isolate salt Peruvian carob gum
which is tara gum
agum monk fruit and with the chocolate
flakes the chocolate flakes are made up
primarily of coconut oil cocoa erythrall
sunflowerless thin salt dutched cocoa
powder natural vanilla flavor and monk
fruit again
which seems a lot considering you just
need chocolate which is three
ingredients and coconut oil but hey
so we know what goes into making their
ice creams
but we come across the biggest issue
which is weights and overrun
so I could actually break down and I
started to do that I broke down the
recipe into the individual components
and created something with the right
amount of
fat and carbs
in
but then that led me to the the biggest
issue is that the serving size which is
89 grams or 90 grams can't remember
and there's three servings per tub so
that tells you how much that tub weighs
all right so 270 280 grams
that's how much our tub weighs which
means that it's almost hot almost half
the weight of a standard tub of Ben and
Jerry's Hogan does
which primarily weigh about 450 to 500
depending on what ice cream you're
buying
with the add-ins in Ben and Jerry's and
Haagen-Dazs they do play around with the
weights somewhat so it becomes difficult
to identify ingredient breakdown
but here it becomes even more difficult
because not only were we trying to deal
with low sugar so low net carbs we're
also trying to determine what their
overrun is now based on that calculation
280 560 as a type is is really heavy
really dense you could do that you could
create a pint of ice cream with 560 gram
weight
but you'll be looking at something with
exceedingly low
maybe even zero overrun I mean milk and
cream alone I think is probably 500
grams so you probably can't get a 560
but you can get close you can get to
500.
but that means you're looking at
something
so dense
it would still probably be nice
but
we kind of then have to say okay with an
overrun close to 100 percent
can we achieve that at home no we can't
but we can't achieve 100 over on home
machines doesn't matter how good your
home machine is you know I've had some
some excellent machines from
you know your box standards uh Cuisinart
ice 100s which I love by the way which
is a great home machine to
you know you both your musos to a Nemo
machine or nemox depending on how you
want to pronounce it machines you can't
get that overrun you have to do that in
a batch freezer and you have to do that
in a good batch freezer too you can't
just buy one of the cheap Viva ones off
Amazon and expect to get 100 over on you
can't do that it won't work
so we're trying to create something here
to imitate something that we already
know we're on the back foot for
but that's okay really the important
thing
for us as home ice cream makers is to
create the best ice cream possible I
don't want to eat
low sugar keto ice cream with 100
overrun I don't want to do that I want
to create a low sugar a keto ice cream
with 30 overrun
which has the same mouth feel texture as
your Häagen-Dazs Belgian chocolate which
is the same texture as your perfect
vanilla the same texture and taste as
your favorite coffee ice cream and I've
made some really good coffee ice creams
so that's what we're going to do today
I'm going to stop yabbouring on and
we're going to make the best keto low
sugar ice cream that you can create in a
home machine with off the shelf
ingredients
started so what are we going to need
we're going to need cream
water let's get these out
we're going to need our cream
with all the with the new camera you can
see all this I mean you can see all the
crap over there so I'll probably just
bring the screen in a bit but you can
see all the stuff and everything so
cream water we're going to need scales
we're definitely going to need scales
we're going to need coffee of some kind
let's use this
you can do this with another coffee if
you like but we'll talk about that in a
second what else we're going to need
we're going to need our sugar substitute
out
early Lowes amazing
inulin
doesn't agree with me
doesn't agree with me but you know
you've got to do what you got to do
skim milk powder egg yolks
and stabilizer skim milk powder
not a lot needed yeah egg yolks
and stabilizer my tire gum
my tire gum hasn't turned up yet should
turn up
next week
there we go let's get everything
measured and weighed and into a pan so
we can pop it on the hob and get it all
dissolved up right let's get our pot
on here and get started I'll go through
the breakdown of ingredients
after we've done it but we're going to
start with keto which is high fat low
sugar or low carbs I should say rather
than sugar
so we're going to start with our 400
grams of cream
a lot of cream there we go
402 grams of cream
and to that we're going to need 100
grams of water
100 grams is 100 milliliters just in
case you're unaware
just like that but we won't put that in
straight away
we're actually I'm gonna start again
we're gonna do 100 grams
okay 100 grams of hot water
[Music]
all right 100 grams of hot water and to
that we're going to add 15 grams of
coffee so obviously this is instant
coffee if you want to use
a different method for coffee use
whatever method
you want so if you've got drip coffee
then make a hundred grams of drip coffee
if you have espresso
make 100 grams of espresso if you
whatever method of coffee you you've got
then make that into your 100 grams
coffee anyway that that's what we've got
so we're going to stir that up to
dissolve the coffee granules
and we're gonna put our 100 grams of
coffee straight in there nice and easy
I'm gonna
reuse that jug
quick wash up
you don't want to make too many things
dirty
so we already know as well in this
recipe that
there
caffeine content is 90
is 90 milligrams per tub so
that's that's why leave that there
that's why we've gone for that much
coffee so we've got our cream we've got
our water we've got our we've got our
coffee in there we're now going to add
in 130 grams of
sugar
substitute early Lowes
130 grams
there's a lot of fruit that has
allylose in it
talk about those later in the video
there we go 130 grams of alibose we're
going to use 30 grams of inulin
yeah
I'm going to use 20 grams of skim milk
powder
like that
and the last couple of things are egg
yolks and our stabilizer so we need 90
grams of egg yolks which I think should
be three
but let's see
these are a bit small so it might be
four
90 grams of our egg yolks
and a stabilizer and I should have put
this in before
but I didn't so I'm just gonna take
a little spoonful of
our alley Lowes
just
a couple of grams
and we're gonna weigh out
we'll do that
I'm gonna weigh out
our stabilizer
and we're gonna go solid
2 grams
okay two gram stabilizer
and we're just gonna
mix that up
egg yolks go in cold
don't have to worry about
all the other junk that people
try and convince you to do and we'll put
this on the hob
we're just gonna
stir it all together
get it all mixed up get your sugars
dissolving get your milk powder
dissolving get your egg yolks mixed up
get it all going don't be don't be shy
just
get it mixed up you need
to make sure all of those ingredients
are properly combined
and what we'll do is We'll add in our
stabilizer
now
and I'll come back in a couple of
minutes okay that's it we're just
warming it up we've got to kind of
steaming Point as we know that's
somewhere between 65 and 80 degrees
we're gonna we're just keeping it there
for a couple of minutes
just to make sure that that stabilizer
is completely activated
and then we're going to take it off the
heat and pop it in a container
right
let's get our gorgeous looking mix
in the container
look at all the lack of egg yolk in
there
I don't know why people in system
doing stuff the hard way but they do so
we're going to pop that in the fridge
until probably
[Music]
okay
well
it's Sunday morning I've got my lounge
pants on back to the old days of filming
in the Cookie Monsters we're gonna get
this fired up get it pre-chilling for 10
minutes and we're gonna get that ice
cream in there churning away
a dog
get the mix out the fridge
you don't have to put the lids on
it's up to you what you do it doesn't
really make a lot of difference we're
going to get a whisk
and just
agitate it
good viscosity on this
yeah that looks
pretty good nice strong smell of coffee
as well so let's
good stuff right let's get this in the
machine
[Music]
and we'll come back five minutes for the
end to do the chocolate chip beads
just churning we need to prepare our
chocolate this is coffee chip this is
the rebel flavor that we that we're
we're not copying but we're making
a more luxury version of it
their ingredients list for their
chocolate they use is the chip the
chocolate chip element I'll put on the
screen here there's a lot of ingredients
in there
um unnecessary I believe so what we're
going to do is just we're going to go
wee I'm gonna go with this which is
straight out of Safeways it's a 72
chocolate but I don't really want
72 all the way through dark chocolate
and coffee ice creams do go together
really really well
but
I'm gonna soften it a little bit
let's get rid of that
I'm gonna soften it a bit with a little
bit of milk chocolate this is balcolade
from Bulk Barn absolutely no idea what
percentage it is so
Broadband if you fancy putting some
information on your lists for on your
tags for people to see what they're
buying that would be helpful
we're going to chop this up don't have
to go too small with it just makes it
easier
for melting
and we're going to put it in a microwave
safe
Bowl
and we're gonna straticello this
I always say say stratageela is not
stretchy attella we're going to stretchy
tell us which means we're going to pour
it in at the end
um
I do like
and the original Belgian chocolate
Haagen-Dazs Belgian chocolate video I
chopped that one the chocolate for that
and it was really good I do like that do
I prefer it I don't know it's just a
kind of different texture but we're
going to make life easy on ourselves
here
so we're going to add some fat into this
and that's what's needed to make it
pourable
normally people add coconut oil
it works really well it's cheap you know
get the deodorized stuff the the
you can buy two different types of
coconut oil one tastes like coconut one
doesn't get the one that doesn't unless
you want your chocolate to say it's
coconut of course so
we're going to use olive oil
the olive oil
I used
in the last
remember what video it was
man that was really good just add this
other little level of taste to your
chocolate anyway we're going to pop that
in the microwave and melt it probably do
it in
yeah 15 seconds 10 15 second stints
if you're melting in a microwave take it
out whilst there's still a couple of
lumps of chocolate left in there if you
try and melt it all directly you're
going to overheat your chocolate
so you can take it out Stir It And if
the chocolate has started to melt it
will melt itself we need just a few more
seconds on this to get it all melted but
it's a much safer way of melting
chocolate
in a microwave
people often ask when does the
temperature take it out somewhere around
-12 is the perfect kind of temperature
to start to Counting from a machine
we're at -9 at the moment so we're
getting there when we get to about minus
10 minus 11 then we're gonna put our
chocolate inside
okay
let's get it loaded up
right
get this loaded up and then into the
freezer
all loaded up
[Music]
hello
let's get this in the freezer
till tomorrow
[Music]
foreign
here we go this is the
Rebel coffee chip
equivalent for you guys to make at home
a the low sugar no sugar however you
want to describe it keto friendly so
it's high fat no sugar
to note is that when you look at the
ingredients for the rebel ice cream it's
basically impossible to figure out
exactly what their recipe is it gives
you the ingredients yes and it does give
you the kind of breakdown of of what
they are but you've got no idea what
their overrun is so without knowing what
their ice cream base weighs before they
turn it I got no way of knowing
exactly what their recipe is so what
we've done is we've just kind of
bypassed that taken the flavor to a
degree and made it into a no sugar high
fat ice cream that is suitable for keto
friendly diets and it is high fat you
know it's over 20 I don't know how this
one's going to work out with with the
cream that I have available here it
might be horrible and greasy we'll find
out in a minute
but I will also start doing some no
sugar ice creams with standard fat
percentages and we'll also do zero sugar
gelato as well so that will be low fat
low sugar recipes that'll be interesting
let's get some scooped up in a bowl
let's see what this looks like
[Music]
it's scooped really nicely
actually better than I thought it would
so that's because
super strong coffee smell again you can
use any coffee you like if you like drip
coffee make a whatever it is 120
did I say 120 grams
115 grams of of your coffee
drip coffee just you know just make it
measure it out weigh it do weigh it
if you want to use coffee beans steeped
in the water then do that if you want to
use instant coffee do that whatever you
want to use coffee wise just make up 115
grams worth
and use that in this recipe
all right if it's too strong
then don't use as much coffee next time
you're strong coffee is there such a
thing
[Music]
that's good
that is good
strong coffee flavor
that
chocolate structure teller throughout
really nice
whatsoever great texture
no greasiness either which is a big
surprise to me considering
you know I I tried a 17 or 16 fat recipe
with the cream over here it was shocking
but maybe it was the combination of the
cream and the milk who knows all I'm
gonna experiment on that as we go and
see how high we can take this but
as you see in the uh in the description
below is the full breakdown it's super
high fat but it's it's got the same
texture that your Luxury Ice Cream has
so your Haagen-Dazs and your Ben and
Jerry's that's something to note here
we've not gone for the 100
look at this look this is what I've done
to try and calculate
exactly how much
break or exactly what the breakdown is
of rebels ice cream I got so confused I
just stopped
and I wanted to make that a keto ice
cream that is as good as the best ice
cream available out there that does have
sugar in it that's what you've got here
you could put this ice cream against any
other ice cream out there and it would
hold up
amazingly well really really well no one
would know that it's got no sugar in it
hands down nobody would know this has no
sugar in it at all let me know if you
want more keto ice cream you want more
low sugar ice cream let me know in the
description below and I'll make sure
that we get through these because I'm
quite happy having no sugar ice cream
means I can eat more anyway
thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like And subscribe I'm gonna
eat this whole tub and not feel guilty
about it and I'll
foreign
[Music]